# **Mohammed Abdulsalam**

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

### **BACK END DEVELOPER**

I am a highly skilled software engineer with over 3 years of experience in PHP and MySQL. I know popular frameworks such as Laravel. I worked on several projects using native PHP and MySQL/MariaDB, as well as projects using Laravel, and have experience designing REST APIs.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : PHP, SQL, Javascript, TeX

**Frameworks** : Laravel, PHPUnit

Libraries : laravel-websockets, laravel-medialibrary, laravel-echo

**Databases** : MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite

: OOP, Design Patterns, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, OAuth, ERD Design, SRS Design Concepts

**Dev Tools** : Vim, XDebug, Vite, Git, Github Actions, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, SSH, cron, Docker

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Developer**

Storiagate

Mar 2024 - Present Hybrid – Alexandria, Egypt

Location: Alexandria, Egypt

- · Redesign company system and forms
- Made reusable components and modules using PHP, SCSS, and Javascript
- · Ensure the cross-browser compatibility of the components
- Developed localization utilities same interface as Laravel to support multible languages
- · Refactored the codebase to reduce complexity and redundancy, and to enhance cohesion
- Maintained the website on a linux server

**Back End Developer** Feb 2022 - Present

Freelance

- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- · Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

#### **Vice Head of Web Development Committee**

GDSC KSU

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023 Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science GPA: 3.3/4

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 - Jun 2024

**Online Chat** Demo

PHP, Laravel, HMVC, SCSS

Private

- Online customer service chat written in PHP / Laravel. Build with HMVC architectural pattern
- Utilized laravel-websockets & laravel-echo to provide real time communication
- Used laravel-medialibrary to facilitate media storing and retrieval
- Developed REST API for clients, and chat frontend using Blade and Javascript

**Bookopia** Demo PHP, Laravel, MVC, SCSS Source Code

- · A library management system written in PHP / Laravel. Build with MVC architectural pattern
- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, and SCSS
- Utilized Laravel Components to enhance the modularity of the frontend
- Extended Blade funcionality by writing customized Directives, that help us write less code

**Salem Clinic Website** PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git Private

- Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a cronjob to backup data periodically

## **Clinic Management System (ERP)**

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned ERD based on this analysis
- Used XDebug to facilitate debugging process, and PHPUnit to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used Socket.IO under Node.js to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

• ITI - Web Development Using PHP (150 hrs.)